Claude Sturgeon

BIM Manager

Cherry Hill, NJ - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Claude-Sturgeon/0195e5ba1a1ac798

As a BIM manager, Claude has helped several construction companies implement BIM - from setting up new BIM standards, to solving complex design issues using the BIM model, making sure that the customer gets early and lasting benefits from their investment in the BIM technology. He has 21 years of combined experience with 10 years in BIM technologies. Claude is a pure enthusiast, who is always more than willing to share his enthusiasm and knowledge of BIM. With over 19 years of IT, he has a strong knowledge of all things hardware and software related. He is a true believer of BIM methodologies, passionate about changes the AEC industry is going thru and is proud to be an active part of it.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Specialist

Virtual Resource Management Corporation - Cherry Hill, NJ - February 2016 to Present

Responsibilities

- 3D structural design using Revit on a ethylene oxide plant
- 3D mechanical equipment design at LOD 500 on a pharmaceutical facility
- · Architectural Revit design pharmaceutical facility
- Coordination and clash detection using NavisWorks
- Train employees on the use of advanced Revit commands and family creation

Consultant

Self Employed - Birmingham, AL - 2015 to 2016

- 3D modeling for various architectural projects in residential and commercial buildings
- 3D rendering for proposals
- Revit construction documents production
- Convert 2D DWG plans to 3D Revit plans
- Create 3D MEPFP Revit models

BIM Electrical Design Engineer

Johnson Service - Council Bluffs, IA - 2014 to 2015

- Update as-built model per field construction
- LOD 500
- Train designers to use Revit 2014/2015
- · Manage Revit model files on sever and delivery to Client
- Ran clash detection on electrical model against other trades
- Design Cable tray telecom system for DC Floor
- Design bus ducts
- Low voltage systems design
- Fire alarm systems

Consultant BIM Manager

Airbus - Birmingham, AL - 2014 to 2014

-2014

- Managed BIM coordination and clash on the AirBus project in Mobile, Al
- Review and Verify that 3D models meet quality expectations
- Develop BIM Schedule per Project
- Work with Subs as required to develop 3D model
- BIM modeling for all disciplines
- Clash Detection

BIM Manager

Roy Anderson Corporation - Gulfport, MS - 2012 to 2014

- BIM Modeling for all disciplines
- Managed Clash Detection using Tekla BIMsight and NavisWorks
- · Managed BIM coordination with contractors to resolve clash areas
- BIM project estimating based on scope of work and plans submitted from engineers
- Development of Facilities Management system in ASP.net Develop BIM pricing for bid packages
- MEP design & 3D modeling
- Write BIM Execution Plan
- · Held BIM kickoff meeting and coordination meetings

Project BIM Manager

Brice Building - Birmingham, AL - 2011 to 2012

- BIM modeling for all disciplines
- Managed clash detection
- Managed BIM coordination with contractors to resolve clash issues
- · Create point coordinates for plumbing and electrical disciplines and convert for surveying equipment use
- MEP design & 3D design
- Developed BIM Guide lines and standards
- BIM project estimating based on scope of work and plans submitted from engineers

Network Administrator/Senior Cad Manager

CTSM Architects Inc - Birmingham, AL - 2007 to 2012

- Developed detail drawings as needed
- Established company Cad standards for ADT platform
- Developed AutoCAD drawing templates to insure transition into ADT while maintaining project schedules
- DNS setup and maintenance from changing ISP Developed training lessons for Cad department personnel on ADT
- Setup work stations and installed software as needed for projects
- Revit Modeling Architectural/Structural and VDC modeling for presentations

Owner Architectural/Structural Design/Network Administrator

CTSM Architects Inc - Birmingham, AL - 2007 to 2012

- Single family custom home designs from 2000 sq ft to 31,000 sq ft
- Design of small multifamily units for private clients, Architects, and local builders of North Carolina, Alabama, Florida, and Georgia
- Contracted through Florez and Florez, Osiris, Axiom Construction Group LLC, Deemer Architect, and Tranquil
 Harbor Development LLC, and many others for design/drafting services on residential homes, commercial
 condominiums, Hospitals and town houses
- Structural design on commercial buildings, stairways, and platforms, with special attention to details and sections, consisting of concrete, wood, and steel construction

- · Design business network configuration and installation
- Windows Home Server setup and maintenance
- Project management
- MEP 3D drawings for commercial buildings
- BIM Modeling/Coordination and VDC rendering

CAD Administrator/Architectural Design/IT Manager

CTSM Architects Inc - Pensacola, FL - 2007 to 2007

-2007

- Designed governmental and military facilities
- Established company Cad standards to meet military requirements
- Developed AutoCAD drawing templates to insure accurate and precise drawings in a timely manner
- Project Job Captain to oversee check sets, communicated with various disciplines, and coordinated drawings with various disciplines to insure project schedules were maintained
- Setup work stations and installed software as needed for projects
- Company website design and maintenance
- · Linux Server maintenance and performed system backups
- FTP setup and maintenance
- Developed cad standards handbook
- Checked architectural drawings for accuracy with other disciplines

CAD Administrator/Architectural Designer

BDA Realty & Construction - Corolla, NC - 2000 to 2003

- Development and implementation of ADT and BD&A standards
- Trained department employees to use ADT 3.3 and 2004
- Design of Beach Homes ranging from 200,000 to over 1 million dollars
- Drawings to include structural, foundation, HVAC, electrical, elevations, and floor plans
- Computer troubleshooting and managed network for CAD department
- Installation and development of software per cad department needs

Mechanical/Structural Designer

American Mechanical Dredge - Mount Juliet, TN - 1999 to 2000

- · Mechanical & Structural design of clamshell dredges for fabrication of working dredge
- Extensive internal pontoon structural design for vibration and stress loads
- Complete design of hydraulic rake drive system. Company acquired patent on design
- Worked closely with fabrication shop on fabrication of dredges
- Management of cad files and correspondence with fabrication shop
- Setup and implantation of CAD standards and PNP network
- Repair and troubleshoot company computer problems both hardware and software for CAD department and other internal departments
- 3D drawings of dredge
- Bill of materials generated from engineered plans for cost evaluation

Mechanical/Electrical/Piping Designer

LaPorte, TX - 1995 to 1999

- Electrical, Mechanical, and Piping design of HDLP/DLP facilities for Exxon, Chevron, and Bayer chemical plants
- Extensive mechanical design of high pressure plastics plant components
- Performed cad/design checking

- · Structural design
- Electrical inspections, one-line updates, and electrical design of high voltage switch gear and distribution
- Construction Superintendent over construction of Bayer Chlorine Plant
- Performed plant start up punch list/walk down Designed PLC and DCS motor control systems of plant units
- Lead designer of Electrical Department
- Head of CAD group
- Repair and troubleshooting computer problems both hardware and software
- Built and upgrade of all workstations

Journeyman

Millwright Union - Baton Rouge, LA - 1975 to 1998

- · General plant maintenance and repair
- · Machine Shop experience running a lathe and various shop equipment

Computer Tech

IBM - Baton Rouge, LA - 1994 to 1995

- Service, install and repair of home PC, network systems, and point of sale for the Greater Baton Rouge area businesses
- Build and upgrade of home/office computers and servers

Owner

Galactic Satellites - Baton Rouge, LA - 1993 to 1994

- · Sales and installation of satellite equipment
- General office work and managing small work force

Certified welder on stick, mig and tig

Gulf States Utilities - Baton Rouge, LA - 1978 to 1994

Baton Rouge, LA

Mechanical Maintenance 1978-1994

- River Bend Nuclear Power Station
- Perform plant maintenance and repairs on electrical and mechanical pumps, valves, compressors, cooling units, motors and hydraulic equipment
- · Repairs and service on heavy equipment and company vehicles
- · Certified welder on stick, mig and tig
- I.B.E.W. Union Steward for 8 years

Business Manager/Paint and Body Work

Gulf States Utilities - Baton Rouge, LA - 1978 to 1987

- Prepared automobile estimates for individuals and Insurance Companies
- · Maintain inventory in warehouse
- Paint and Body work on automobiles

EDUCATION

Associates in Technical Design

I.T.I. Technical College - Baton Rouge, LA 1994 to 1995

North Dallas College - Baton Rouge, LA

General

Cleveland Institution of Electronics - Cleveland, OH 1987 to 1988

Electrical Engineering

Louisiana State University - Baton Rouge, LA 1978

SKILLS

• AutoCAD 12 thru 2016 (10+ years), , AutoCAD MEP 2011 thru 2016 (5 years), , MicroStation (4 years), Revit (9 years), NavisWorks (9 years), Tekla BIMsight (7 years), • Synchro (2 years), 3DS Max (3 years), • Visual Studio 2010 (4 years), • Microsoft Office Professional (10+ years), • BIM Modeling for all disciplines (9 years), BIM Manager (8 years)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Skills

- AutoCAD 12 thru 2016, AutoCAD MEP 2011 thru 2016, MicroStation, Sketch UP
- AutoCAD Architectural 3.3 thru 2016, Revit Architectural, Revit MEP [...]
- BIM Coordination & Clash Detection using NavisWorks 2016, Tekla BIMsight
- BIM 360 Glue, BIManywhere Pro,
- Bluebeam, Submittal Exchange
- Revit family creation to LOD 500 level
- Revit MEP- Modeling and design of all systems
- NavisWorks-4D simulation, VDC & Animation using P6 construction schedules
- Revit Design and Modeling abilities
- Synchro- 4D Simulation
- 5D- Cost Loaded Models
- 6D- Developed & Coded Facilities Management System in Asp.net
- VDC- Lumion, 3DS Max and Revit Rendering, Presentation and Animation for project proposals
- Visual Studio 2010
- Windows 7/8.1, Windows 10
- Microsoft Office Professional
- Adobe Photoshop
- Hardware troubleshooting, building, and installation of servers, laptops, and desktop pc's.
- Installation of operating systems, drivers and various software
- Cat 5, 6 cable install & repairs